<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Cambridge Software Craftsmanship Community blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://camswcraft.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://camswcraft.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-01T12:32:17+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://camswcraft.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alastair Smith]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2014 Workshop: Extreme Startup With Carlos Fernandez Garcia and Emanuele Blanco]]></title>
    <link href="http://camswcraft.github.io/blog/2014/07/29/july-2014-workshop-extreme-startup-with-carlos-fernandez-garcia-and-emanuele-blanco/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-29T19:17:56+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://camswcraft.github.io/blog/2014/07/29/july-2014-workshop-extreme-startup-with-carlos-fernandez-garcia-and-emanuele-blanco</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our workshop this month was Rob Chatley&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="https://github.com/rchatley/extreme_startup">Extreme Startup</a>&rdquo;, run by
<a href="https://twitter.com/villademor">Carlos Fernandez Garcia</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/manub">Emanuele Blanco</a> of the
<a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-software-craftsmanship/">London Software Craftsmanship Community</a>. Extreme Startup is
based on a question-and-answer format: you register an HTTP server with the Extreme Startup game, and it sends you
questions as HTTP requests.</p>

<p>After a few technology hiccoughs with the internet connection (note to future self: check this beforehand!), we were
underway with the warmup round, and had seven teams registered with the server.</p>

<p>The first round focussed on keeping the application running: we learned that the customer is more upset to get no
response at all than to get an incorrect response. The questions in this round were fairly simple maths-based questions:
&ldquo;what is 1 + 10&rdquo;, &ldquo;what is the largest of these numbers: 99, 3, 67&rdquo;, etc.</p>

<p>The next round introduced a change in requirements; there&rsquo;s no room to get complacent in this exercise! Suddenly we were
hit with harder maths questions like &ldquo;which of these numbers are a cube and a square&rdquo;? One team, taking the innovative
approach of handing off to Wolfram Alpha to answer the questions, quickly took the lead; another team, opting for an
interactive approach to answering the questions, were in second place. Luckily there&rsquo;s no bonus for a quick answer!</p>

<p>The third round upped the stakes further: now we had to handle non-maths questions, like &ldquo;Who played James Bond in Dr.
No?&rdquo;. This stretched even the hardiest of solutions.</p>

<p>Overall it was a great workshop, which everyone attending enjoyed very much. Unsurprisingly the Wolfram Alpha team
scored the most points, and with a large lead. There was strong competition between one implementation that always
returned <em>something</em>, whether or not it was correct, and the team calculating the answers by hand. If you get a chance
to participate in an Extreme Startup workshop, I highly recommend you take it!</p>

<h2>Retrospective</h2>

<p>Interestingly, only two teams wrote tests for their solution, and no teams used any kind of source control. Of the
pairs, most were using driver-navigator pairing, but one used ping-pong pairing.</p>

<p>Starting again, people would choose the technologies they are familiar with to ensure a solid start.</p>

<p><strong>Want to share your experience?</strong> <a href="https://github.com/camswcraft/camswcraft.github.io">Fork this blog on GitHub</a>.</p>

<h2>Thanks</h2>

<p>Thanks to Carlos and Emanuele for running the workshop so well and remaining cool under pressure, and to
<a href="http://www.grantadesign.com/">Granta Design</a> for hosting us!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://camswcraft.github.io/blog/2014/07/28/Hello-World/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-28T14:21:26+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://camswcraft.github.io/blog/2014/07/28/Hello-World</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the new Cambridge Software Craftsmanship Community blog. The purpose of this blog is to document the meetings
of the Community, including useful outcomes and tidbits from our round-tables, notes and documentation from the
workshops.</p>

<h2>Who are we?</h2>

<p>We are a regular <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cambridge-Software-Craftsmanship/">Meetup group</a> for software developers who
care about and take pride in what they do and how they do it.  Modelled on the London Software Craftsmanship Community,
I hope to bring some of their success to the Cambridge software community.</p>

<p>Software Craftsmanship has grown out of Agile, with many of the leading lights in the Craftsmanship movement being the
founders of the Agile movement as well.</p>

<p>The Software Craftsmanship Manifesto describes the movement as follows:</p>

<blockquote><p>As aspiring Software Craftsmen we are raising the bar of professional software development by practicing it and
helping others learn the craft. Through this work we have come to value:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not only working software, but also well-crafted software</li>
<li>Not only responding to change, but also steadily adding value</li>
<li>Not only individuals and interactions, but also a community of professionals</li>
<li>Not only customer collaboration, but also productive partnerships
That is, in pursuit of the items on the left we have found the items on the right to be indispensable.</li>
</ul>


<p>© 2009, the undersigned.  This statement may be freely copied in any form, but only in its entirety through this
notice.</p></blockquote>

<p>Through this group, I hope to tackle the third point from the manifesto and create and encourage a community of
professionals in the Cambridge area.</p>

<h2>What meetings do you run?</h2>

<h3>Round-Table Discussions</h3>

<p>We meet regularly on the first Tuesday of each month at <a href="http://www.red-gate.com/">Red Gate Software</a> for a Round-Table
Discussion. The format of these meetings is open and welcoming to all. Topics are decided by the group from a selection
proposed by attendees on the night, potentially following on from preceding lightning talks. We normally cover a couple
of topics, and occasionally split into smaller groups to discuss separate subjects.</p>

<p>Lightning talks are short-format presentations, optionally including slides, lasting no more than 5 minutes. You do not
need to have anything prepared in advance, just turn up and talk!</p>

<h3>Workshops</h3>

<p>Often, we meet on the third Tuesday of the month at <a href="http://www.grantadesign.com/">Granta Design</a> for an interactive
workshop. These cover varying aspects of programming, including test-driven development, refactoring, object-oriented
design, or functional programming. We have also delved into new languages such as Clojure and Haskell, and learned about
hard computing problems like machine learning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
