<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://camswcraft.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://camswcraft.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-28T14:46:05+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://camswcraft.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alastair Smith]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://camswcraft.github.io/blog/2014/07/28/Hello-World/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-28T14:21:26+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://camswcraft.github.io/blog/2014/07/28/Hello-World</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Hello world!</h1>

<p>Welcome to the new Cambridge Software Craftsmanship Community blog. The purpose of this blog is to document the meetings
of the Community, including useful outcomes and tidbits from our round-tables, notes and documentation from the
workshops.</p>

<h2>Who are we?</h2>

<p>We are a regular <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cambridge-Software-Craftsmanship/">Meetup group</a> for software developers who
care about and take pride in what they do and how they do it.  Modelled on the London Software Craftsmanship Community,
I hope to bring some of their success to the Cambridge software community.</p>

<p>Software Craftsmanship has grown out of Agile, with many of the leading lights in the Craftsmanship movement being the
founders of the Agile movement as well.</p>

<p>The Software Craftsmanship Manifesto describes the movement as follows:</p>

<blockquote><p>As aspiring Software Craftsmen we are raising the bar of professional software development by practicing it and
helping others learn the craft. Through this work we have come to value:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not only working software, but also well-crafted software</li>
<li>Not only responding to change, but also steadily adding value</li>
<li>Not only individuals and interactions, but also a community of professionals</li>
<li>Not only customer collaboration, but also productive partnerships
That is, in pursuit of the items on the left we have found the items on the right to be indispensable.</li>
</ul>


<p>© 2009, the undersigned.  This statement may be freely copied in any form, but only in its entirety through this
notice.</p></blockquote>

<p>Through this group, I hope to tackle the third point from the manifesto and create and encourage a community of
professionals in the Cambridge area.</p>

<h2>What meetings do you run?</h2>

<h3>Round-Table Discussions</h3>

<p>We meet regularly on the first Tuesday of each month at <a href="http://www.red-gate.com/">Red Gate Software</a> for a Round-Table
Discussion. The format of these meetings is open and welcoming to all. Topics are decided by the group from a selection
proposed by attendees on the night, potentially following on from preceding lightning talks. We normally cover a couple
of topics, and occasionally split into smaller groups to discuss separate subjects.</p>

<p>Lightning talks are short-format presentations, optionally including slides, lasting no more than 5 minutes. You do not
need to have anything prepared in advance, just turn up and talk!</p>

<h3>Workshops</h3>

<p>Often, we meet on the third Tuesday of the month at <a href="http://www.grantadesign.com/">Granta Design</a> for an interactive
workshop. These cover varying aspects of programming, including test-driven development, refactoring, object-oriented
design, or functional programming. We have also delved into new languages such as Clojure and Haskell, and learned about
hard computing problems like machine learning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
